EMIL CHIGU

• DETAILS •

+44 7507348056 emil@tafaracareservices.com

LINKS

Linked In

<u>Portfolio</u>

SKILLS

Git

Node.js

ReactJS

HTML/CSS/JavaScript

Django

MongoDB

PROFILE

An experienced Web Developer adept in all stages of web development with close to three years experience in the field. In that time having set up a Sass business with over 2000 users. A fast learner who is comfortable tackling any technology with a focus JavaScript and python based web development frameworks. Self-managing during independent projects, as well as collaborative in a team setting.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

IT Manager at Tafara Care Services, Johannesburg

August 2019 — Present

IT administrator with the below achievements above my day to day job:

- Building a full-stack in-house web application to automate repetitive tasks in the compliance department including document generation using the MERN stack
- Making the business more accessible to customers by building a mobile responsive and SEO-friendly website to showcase the company's services.
- Designed and implemented the majority of IT and information security-related policies

Co-Founder / Product Development Lead at Assegai Nutrition, Johannesburg

March 2017 — August 2019

Outside the development of nutritional products, increased the company's customer base by creating a full e-commerce website using WordPress and Woo-commerce with full online payment integration.

(Besides static websites, this was one of my biggest undertakings at the time.)

Freelancer Web Develoepr at Self, Bristol

February 2019 — Present

Developed a number of websites for individuals and businesses over the years.

EDUCATION

Honours, Nutrition Science, University of Zimbabwe, Harare

September 2012 — September 2016

International Baccalaureate, St Georges British International School of Rome, Rome September 2004 — September 2010

I was granted the principal's business studies award.

COURSES

The web Developer Bootcamp, Udemy

January 2020 — March 2022

Comptia Security+, Comptia

March 2022 — Present

Python and Django Full Stack Web Developer Bootcamp, Udemy

September 2022 — December 2021

React - The complete Guide, Udemy September 2020 — October 2020

▼ REFERENCES

Keith Busumani from Tafara Care Services

keith@tafaracareservices.com · +447885606668

Bradley Magumura from Assegai Nutrition

bnmagum@gmail.com · +27673034162